<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Internet Marketing | GeeKhmer]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/categories/internet-marketing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-07-11T00:09:24+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Bunlong Van]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[bunlong.van@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simple Sales Framework for "Sell me this pen"]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2017/04/03/sell-me-this-pen/"/>
    <updated>2017-04-03T22:19:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2017/04/03/sell-me-this-pen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/sell_me_this_pen.png" width="600" alt="Sell me this pen" />
</p>




<p>
  I personally never thought anyone would say, "Sell me this pen" in a sales interview. I was wrong. It will happen to you. And you should know exactly what to say back.
</p>




<p>
  I will give you the right sales framework to respond perfectly every time. One day it will happen to you and I want you prepare the script as below:
</p>




<p>
  Here we go:
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Interviewer: Do me a favor, sell me this pen. (reaches across to hand me the pen)</strong>
</p>




<p>
  Me: (I slowly roll the pen between my index and thumb fingers.) When was the last time you used a pen?
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Interviewer: This morning.</strong>
</p>




<p>
  Me: Do you remember what kind of pen that was?
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Interviewer: No.</strong>
</p>




<p>
  Me: Do you remember why you were using it to write?
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Interviewer: Yes. Signing a few new customer contracts.</strong>
</p>




<p>
  Me: Well I'd say that's the best use for a pen.
</p>




<p>
  Would not you say signing those new customer contracts is an important event for the business? Then you shouldn't treate like this. What I mean is, here you are signing new customer contracts, an important and memorable event with a very unmemorable pen.
</p>




<p>
  This is the pen for more important events. This is the tool you use to get deals done. Think of it as a symbol for taking your company to the next level. Because when you begin using the right tool, you are in a more productive state of mind, and you begin to sign more new customer contracts.
</p>




<p>
  Actually. You know? Just this week I shipped ten new boxes of these pens to many office in Phnom Penh.
</p>




<p>
  Unfortunately, this is my last pen today. So, I suggest you get this one. Try it out. If you are not happy with it, I will personally come back next week to pick it up. And it won't cost you a dime. What do you say?
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Interviewer: Yes.</strong>
</p>




<p>
  See how simple that was. The Interviewer/Customer loved it. Why?
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Here's the Simple Sales Framework for "Sell me this pen"</strong><br/>
  1. <code>Gather info</code> - Find out how they last used a pen<br/>
  2. <code>Respond to info</code> - Emphasize the importance of the activity they last used a pen<br/>
  3. <code>Delivery info</code> - Sell something bigger than a pen, like a state of mind<br/>
  4. <code>Closing</code> - Ask for the buy
</p>




<p>
  So far so good, remember it's not about actually selling a pen. It's about showing how well you can sell a product. Take 15 minutes today to practice the script above. I promise you will benefit. Share this with person in sales. It could save their career lolzzZ. See ya!
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generating Income on the Internet Using Social Media]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2017/03/21/generating-income-on-the-internet-using-social-media/"/>
    <updated>2017-03-21T10:56:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2017/03/21/generating-income-on-the-internet-using-social-media</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/internet_marketing.png" width="600" alt="Generating Income on the Internet Using Social Media" />
</p>




<p>
  Once it comes to generating income on the Internet using social media, there are a few principles which you need to understand.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>1. INTRODUCE YOURSELF</strong><br/>
  The first thing you need to know is how to introduce yourself, whether video or article platform.
</p>




<p>
  People are busy, you need to think of how you can introduce yourself in under 15 seconds. Get to the right point.
</p>




<p>
  Take sometime to come up with a way to do it, and remember the words you used because you’ll need to do it the same way every time you introduce yourself on the same platform.
</p>




<p>
  As well, keep in mind that among the people who log into your scope, some might not have heard of you before, so you need to not just introduce yourself quickly, but you need to be able to capture and hold their attention/interest.
</p>




<p>
  Within that 15 seconds of your introduction, you need to be able to make people understand who you are and what you do.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>2. HAVE A PRODUCT TO PROMOTE</strong><br/>
  The second thing that you will need to have is a product to promote.
</p>




<p>
  There are two ways for you to do this:<br/>
  - Promote your own product for 100% of the profit<br/>
  - Promote someone else’s product for a commission
</p>




<p>
  You decide – you could sell a product on Amazon, Alibabaor or sell a product yourself on your own website or mobile platform.<br/>
</p>




<p>
  You must have a product!
</p>




<p>
  <strong>3. HAVE A CALL TO ACTION</strong><br/>
  The third thing you need is a call to action – What is "A call to action"? It mean that you must tell people what to do next.
</p>




<p>
  If you don’t have a call to action, then no action will be taken.
</p>




<p>
  At the end of the scope tell people that:
</p>




<p>
  "If you like what you have just known, head over or go through to my website."
</p>




<p>
  Or you could tell them: "If you liked this scope, please follow me on twitter, facebook page... and join me for the next one."
</p>




<p>
  Every time you present, you must always have a call to action.
</p>




<p>
  So these are the three things that you want to have to really master and get thousands of people to your social media. So far so good, That's it!!! See ya!!! :)
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
