<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Internet Marketing | GeeKhmer]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/categories/internet-marketing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-03-27T01:23:04+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Bunlong Van]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[bunlong.van@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generating Income on the Internet Using Social Media]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2017/03/21/generating-income-on-the-internet-using-social-media/"/>
    <updated>2017-03-21T10:56:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2017/03/21/generating-income-on-the-internet-using-social-media</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/internet_marketing.png" width="600" alt="Generating Income on the Internet Using Social Media" />
</p>




<p>
  Once it comes to generating income on the Internet using social media, there are a few principles which you need to understand.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>1. INTRODUCE YOURSELF</strong><br/>
  The first thing you need to know is how to introduce yourself, whether video or article platform.
</p>




<p>
  People are busy, you need to think of how you can introduce yourself in under 15 seconds. Get to the right point.
</p>




<p>
  Take sometime to come up with a way to do it, and remember the words you used because you’ll need to do it the same way every time you introduce yourself on the same platform.
</p>




<p>
  As well, keep in mind that among the people who log into your scope, some might not have heard of you before, so you need to not just introduce yourself quickly, but you need to be able to capture and hold their attention/interest.
</p>




<p>
  Within that 15 seconds of your introduction, you need to be able to make people understand who you are and what you do.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>2. HAVE A PRODUCT TO PROMOTE</strong><br/>
  The second thing that you will need to have is a product to promote.
</p>




<p>
  There are two ways for you to do this:<br/>
  - Promote your own product for 100% of the profit<br/>
  - Promote someone else’s product for a commission
</p>




<p>
  You decide – you could sell a product on Amazon, Alibabaor or sell a product yourself on your own website or mobile platform.<br/>
</p>




<p>
  You must have a product!
</p>




<p>
  <strong>3. HAVE A CALL TO ACTION</strong><br/>
  The third thing you need is a call to action – What is "A call to action"? It mean that you must tell people what to do next.
</p>




<p>
  If you don’t have a call to action, then no action will be taken.
</p>




<p>
  At the end of the scope tell people that:
</p>




<p>
  "If you like what you have just known, head over or go through to my website."
</p>




<p>
  Or you could tell them: "If you liked this scope, please follow me on twitter, facebook page... and join me for the next one."
</p>




<p>
  Every time you present, you must always have a call to action.
</p>




<p>
  So these are the three things that you want to have to really master and get thousands of people to your social media. So far so good, That's it!!! See ya!!! :)
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
