<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Other | GeeKhmer]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/categories/other/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2018-04-15T21:57:32+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Bunlong Van]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[bunlong.van@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progressive &amp; Lazy Loading Image with lazy-load-images.js]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2018/04/15/progressive-and-lazy-loading-image-with-lazy-load-images-dot-js/"/>
    <updated>2018-04-15T18:08:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2018/04/15/progressive-and-lazy-loading-image-with-lazy-load-images-dot-js</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/lazy-load-images.png" width="700" alt="Lazy load images" />
</p>




<p>
  With images making up a whopping 65% of all web content, page load time on websites can easily become an issue.
</p>




<p>
  Images can weight quite a bit. This can have a negative impact on the time visitors have to wait before they can access content on your website. they will get navigate somewhere else, unless you come up with a solution to image loading.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>What is lazy loading?</strong><br/>
  Lazy loading images means loading images on websites asynchronously that is, after the content is fully loaded, or even conditionally, only when they appear in the browser’s viewport. This means that if users don’t scroll all the way down, images placed at the bottom of the page won't be loaded.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>What reason you should care of lazy loading images?</strong><br/>
  There are many reasons you should consider of lazy loading images for your website:
</p>




<p>
  If your website uses JavaScript to display content or provide some functionality to users, loading the DOM quickly becomes critical. It’s common for scripts to wait until the DOM has completely loaded before they start running. On a site with a number of images, lazy loading or loading images asynchronously could make the difference between users staying or leaving your website.
</p>




<p>
  Since most lazy loading solutions work by loading images only if the user has scrolled to the location where images would be visible inside the viewport, those images will never be loaded if users never get to that point. This means considerable savings in bandwidth, for which most users, especially those accessing the web on mobile devices and slow-connections.
</p>




<p>
  Lazy loading images helps with website performance, but what’s the best way to go about it?
</p>




<p>
  Well, <a href="https://github.com/codefacebook/lazy-load-images.js" target="_blank">lazy-load-images.js</a> is a javascript library which could help you with the website performance.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>lazy-load-images.js is loading with blurred image effect</strong><br/>
  If you are a Medium reader, you have certainly noticed how the site loads the main image inside a post.
</p>




<p>
  The first thing you see is a blurred, low-resolution copy of the image, while its high-resversion is being lazy loaded:
</p>




<p>
  Blurred placeholder image on <a href="https://lazyloadimages.github.io/" target="_blank">lazy-load-images.js</a> website:
</p>




<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/lazy-load-images-tiny.png" width="700" alt="Lazy load images" />
</p>




<p>
  High-res, lazy loaded image on <a href="https://lazyloadimages.github.io/" target="_blank">lazy-load-images.js</a> website:
</p>




<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/lazy-load-images-full.png" width="700" alt="Lazy load images" />
</p>




<p>
  You can lazy load images with this interesting blurring effect in a number of ways.
</p>




<p>
  My favorite technique/library is using <a href="https://github.com/codefacebook/lazy-load-images.js" target="_blank">lazy-load-images.js</a>. Here’s all the features/goodness:<br/>
  - Fast loading<br/>
  - High performance<br/>
  - Supports all images type<br/>
  - Responsive images<br/>
  - Supports all modern browsers Chrome, Firefox, Safari, (IE10+), ... etc.
</p>




<p>
  You can read all details and download the lazy-load-images.js library on the project's <a href="https://github.com/codefacebook/lazy-load-images.js" target="_blank">GitHub repo</a>.
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Most Popular ReactJs User Interface Frameworks]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2017/11/13/the-most-popular-reactjs-user-interface-frameworks/"/>
    <updated>2017-11-13T21:37:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2017/11/13/the-most-popular-reactjs-user-interface-frameworks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  I was researching for the rich UI frameworks based on ReactJs which give the power of composability through ReactJs components, that you can directly plug in into your ReactJs project. Let go through the list below and pickup the right one.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Material-UI</strong><br/>
  Material-UI is a set of ReactJs components which implement Google's Material Design. <a href="http://www.material-ui.com" target="_blank">Source</a>
</p>




<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/react_material.png" width="600" alt="Material UI" />
</p>




<p>
  <strong>React-Bootstrap</strong><br/>
  Bootstrap is one of the most advanced UI frameworks out there and has got most of the things right. <a href="https://react-bootstrap.github.io" target="_blank">Source</a>
</p>




<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/react_bootstrap.png" width="600" alt="React Bootstrap" />
</p>




<p>
  <strong>React-Foundation</strong><br/>
  Foundation from Zurb is a very feature-rich and easily customizable library. <a href="https://foundation.zurb.com" target="_blank">Source</a>
</p>




<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/react_foundation.png" width="600" alt="React Foundation" />
</p>




<p>
  <strong>React-Semantic</strong><br/>
  Semantic UI React is the official React integration for Semantic UI. <a href="https://react.semantic-ui.com/introduction" target="_blank">Source</a>
</p>




<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/react_semantic.png" width="600" alt="React Semantic" />
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Most Popular ReactJs Data Table]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2017/11/07/the-most-popular-reactjs-data-table/"/>
    <updated>2017-11-07T21:12:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2017/11/07/the-most-popular-reactjs-data-table</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  I've been researching this for many days so I can help you at least find the ones out there. I don't have experience with most of these but the one I do have experience with is one I don't recommend as it seems unmaintained. Though I did find it well documented and easy to use. My requirements aren't particularly complicated for a data-grid component, I basically look at filtering, sorting and row selection. If you need anything more complicated you'll have to dig further into the documentations.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>React-Data-Grid</strong><br/>
  Excel-liked grid component built with React, with editors, keyboard navigation, copy & paste, and the like <a href="http://adazzle.github.io/react-data-grid/" target="_blank">http://adazzle.github.io/react-data-grid</a>.
</p>




<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/react-data-grid.png" width="600" alt="React-Data-Grid" />
</p>




<p>
  <strong>React-Bootstrap-Table</strong><br/>
  It's a ReactJs table for bootstrap, named react-bootstrap-table. It's a configurable, functional table component and make you build a Bootstrap Table more efficiency and easy in your ReactJs application like <a href="https://allenfang.github.io/react-bootstrap-table/" target="_blank">https://allenfang.github.io/react-bootstrap-table</a>.
</p>




<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/react-bootstrap-table.png" width="600" alt="React-Bootstrap-Table" />
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Griddle</strong><br/>
  It's an ultra customizable data-grid component for ReactJs like <a href="http://griddlegriddle.github.io/Griddle/" target="_blank">http://griddlegriddle.github.io/Griddle</a>.
</p>




<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/griddle.png" width="600" alt="Griddle" />
</p>




<p>
  <strong>React-Table</strong><br/>
  React-Table is a lightweight, fast and extendable data-grid built for ReactJs like <a href="https://react-table.js.org/" target="_blank">https://react-table.js.org</a>.
</p>




<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/react-table.png" width="600" alt="React-Table" />
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Create-React-App Vs NextJs]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2017/11/04/create-react-app-vs-nextjs/"/>
    <updated>2017-11-04T22:13:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2017/11/04/create-react-app-vs-nextjs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/cra_vs_next.png" width="600" alt="Create-React-App Vs NextJs" />
</p>




<p>
  <a href="https://github.com/zeit/next.js/" target="_blank">NextJs</a> is a new project with a lot to offer.
</p>




<p>
  The comparison between NextJs and Create-React-App is an apt one. What NextJs brings is great defaults. Like Create-React-App, NextJs is opinionated. It makes choices for you about what an ideal React setup should look like.
</p>




<p>
  One of the biggest pain points in starting a new javascript App is the tooling. Webpack, babel, and the like can be a pain to setup, especially with the aggressive release cycle of open source javascript projects. As of this writing you're probably already using Webpack syntax that's been deprecated.

</p>




<p>
  Here are the biggest differences between Create-React-App and NextJs.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Create-React-App Is Ejectable, NextJs Is Extensible</strong><br/>
</p>




<p>
  Create-React-App uses babel, webpack, and eslint but "hides" this tooling and bundles it together in react-scripts. But Create-React-App doesn't lock you in; when you're ready to depart from training wheels you can unmask these dependencies and then configure them.
</p>




<p>
  NextJs, on the other hand, provides great defaults with the option to configure tooling if you want to. For example, you can override (or extend) NextJs's webpack configuration by adding a webpack.config.js file. Or you can add an express server if you don't want to use NextJs' server.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>NextJs is Out Of The Box</strong>
</p>




<p>
  The biggest point of NextJs is server-side rendering.
</p>




<p>
  People will tell you that Google crawls javascript and that it's sufficient to serve up an almost-empty html document with <code>root</code> class along with a massive bundle.js.
</p>




<p>
  It's true that Google crawls javascript. But this just isn't a good approach for apps that are content-focused and need to expose their content to search. 
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Styling is A Pain With NextJs</strong>
</p>




<p>
  NextJs can be a pain with styling. Out of the box, NextJs uses styled-jsx, which is OK. But what if you want to use SASS or styled-components? You're in for a few hours of frustration.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>You Can't make API Calls In Components With NextJs</strong>
</p>




<p>
  Initializing a new NextJs project creates two directores ./pages and ./components.
</p>




<p>
  Pages are like container React components. But they have more significance than simply wrapping other components. Page components are literally rendered into pages with a little help from react-router. That is, http://localhost:3000/about points to ./pages/about.js. This approach has strengthes and limitations. One of the limitations is that you can only make a client-side fetch request in top-level page components.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Create-React-App Vs NextJs: Comparison Table</strong>
</p>




<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th></th>
      <th>Create React App</th>
      <th>NextJs</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>Dependencies</td>
      <td>One (react-scripts)</td>
      <td>One (next)</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Ejectable</td>
      <td>Yes</td>
      <td>No</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Extensible</td>
      <td>No</td>
      <td>Yes</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Isomorphic/Universal</td>
      <td>No</td>
      <td>Yes</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Zero-configuration</td>
      <td>Yes</td>
      <td>Yes</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Service workers</td>
      <td>Yes</td>
      <td>No</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Hot-reloading</td>
      <td>Yes</td>
      <td>Yes</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Code-splitting</td>
      <td>Can be configured</td>
      <td>Out of the box</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>




<br/>




<p>
  <strong>Conclusion</strong>
</p>




<p>
  NextJs is a good start if you need SSR first, SEO friendly with lots of public content. But if you build a highly dynamic statically deployed Single Page Application client, CRA (Create React App) is better suited for that.
</p>




<p>
  So for blog, news, with lots of public content and shareability, I'll go with NextJs. For dashboard, admin, apps, I'll go with CRA (Create React App)
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is Full Stack Developer?]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2017/06/25/what-is-full-stack-developer/"/>
    <updated>2017-06-25T00:26:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2017/06/25/what-is-full-stack-developer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/full_lstack_developer.jpg" width="600" alt="What is Full Stack Developer?" />
</p>




<p>
  We live in the world of start-ups and freelancers. If you want to make it in such a world, you need to be equipped with the necessary skills.
</p>




<p>
  Big organizations can afford to have developer, designer, tester etc... and roles assigned to different people. 
</p>




<p>
  As the start-up or small organization, such roles assigned to different people may be too costly. It is far much more preferable to have a single person who can work comfortably in all of the above roles.
</p>




<p>
  Gone the days, one needed to know only one language/technology and get with. But these days, you will need to know more than one language/technology. This is where the full-stack developer comes in. A full-stack developer is comfortable working in both the back-end and front-end environments.
</p>




<h3>BACK-END DEVELOPER</h3>




<p>
  Back-end developers are much more focused on what happens on the server-side. This includes writing the code that responds to front-end user requests, interacting with the database and infrastructure for web server as well. One will need to know more than one of the following.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES</strong>
</p>




<p>
  The following are some of the languages that you should know.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>PHP/Laravel</strong><br/>
   PHP is a scripting server-side language. You can use PHP to interact with the database, develop APIs and do a hell lot of things. PHP is open source and almost supported by all hosting environments.
</p>




<p>
  As a full-stack developer, having knowledge of PHP is almost a must. It is a massive advantage but you will need to prove yourself to your employers or clients.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Ruby/Rails</strong><br/>
  Ruby on rails is another popular MVC framework built on ruby. Just like PHP, Ruby on rails is open source. You can use ruby to create web applications and APIs.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>ASP.Net</strong><br/>
  ASP is the acronym for active server pages. It is a web development language developed by Microsoft and runs on the .Net framework.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>JSP</strong><br/>
  JSP is the acronym for Java Server Pages. It is powered by Java and used to create web applications.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>DATABASE ENGINES</strong>
</p>




<p>
  In today’s world, almost all applications must store data in the database. Data is literally the blood line of all modern businesses. Knowing about databases will help you to go a long way
</p>




<p>
  <strong>MySQL</strong><br/>
  MySQL is a client-server relational database management system. It runs on all operating systems and is mostly used with PHP. It supports tables, views, triggers and stored procedures etc. You can also use it with other programming languages such as Ruby, Java, C# etc.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Microsoft SQL Server</strong><br/>
  SQL Server is a commercial relational database management systems developed by Microsoft. It is most commonly used with ASP.Net but you can also use it with other languages i.e. Java, PHP etc.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Sqlite</strong><br/>
  SQLite is an embedded relational SQL database. It is commonly used on mobile devices i.e. smart phones. You can also use it when working with web applications.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Oracle</strong><br/>
  Oracle is another popular relational database management system developed by Oracle. It is most used by big corporations.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>PostgreSQL</strong><br/>
  PostgreSQL (pronounced "post-gress-Q-L") is an open source relational database management system ( DBMS ) developed by a worldwide team of volunteers. PostgreSQL is not controlled by any corporation or other private entity and the source code is available free of charge.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>DEVELOPMENT METHODOLOGIES</strong>
</p>




<p>
  In addition to possessing the technical skills, you will also need to know about project management and development methodologies.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Agile Development Methodologies</strong><br/>
  Agile development is a term that is used to refer to development methodologies that incremental development practices. Some of the most popular methodologies include <a href="http://scrummethodology.com/" target="_blank">Scrum</a> and Extreme Programming (XP).
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Development Tools / Techniques</strong><br/>
  One only needed to know a single programing language, develop something functional and get away with it. Things have changed these days. In additional to knowing at least more than one language. Your skill set should also including: Version Control, Test Driven Development (TDD).
</p>




<h3>FRONT-END DEVELOPER</h3>




<p>
  The major role of a front-end developer is to create the user interface that the user interacts with. This generally requires knowing HTML, CSS, and JavaScript intimately. Let’s briefly look at some of the skills that you will need to know.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Hyper Text Markup Language (HTML)</strong><br/> 
  As of this writing, the latest version of HTML is 5. It comes with a lot of cool features that you must know. Web pages are literally build using HTML.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)</strong><br/>
  Another component of building web pages. CSS provides you with the styling that makes the web beautiful.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>JavaScript (JS)</strong><br/>
  JavaScript is a client-side scripting language that is used to make web pages interactive and provide a lot of functionality. You can use JavaScript to provide client-side validation, performing Ajax calls etc. apart from doing client-side activities, JavaScript can now be used on the server side as well i.e. Node.JS.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>JavaScript Frameworks / Libraries</strong><br/>
  Pure JavaScript is great for simple tasks but things can and usually tend to get more complex. Frameworks and libraries allow you to focus on the user needs while they take care of the technical needs. Libraries such as jQuery allow you to do more with less. jQuery comes with functionality for things like validation, animations, Ajax calls etc. You will also need to know JavaScript frameworks i.e. ReactJS, AngularJS etc. to create killer interactive interfaces.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Front-End Frameworks</strong><br/>
  Time is money you don’t want to spent a lot of time on a project focusing on technical details. You can take advantage of front-end frameworks such as twitter bootstrap to make your life sweet. Twitter bootstrap comes with CSS and JavaScript functionality out of the box. Once you have the design mock-ups, you can focus on applying CSS classes to your HTML elements and watch the magic happen instead of writing the CSS code that will translate your mock-ups to cool HTML pages.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>CSS Pre-Processors </strong><br/>
  These enable you to speed up your CSS development. CSS pre-processors such as SASS and LESS process your CSS code before publishing to make the code cross-browser friendly and well formatted.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Template Engines</strong><br/>
   Let’s assume that you are using PHP on the back-end, before template engines, the front-end developers would create the HTML, handle it over to the developers and then they would embed pure PHP code into the HTML. This is no longer acceptable. You need to learn a template engine and they are super easy actually. Laravel uses blade template.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Responsive and Mobile Designs</strong><br/>
  Your interfaces need to be able to respond to the size of the design and mobile devices.
</p>




<p>
  So far so good, as you can see from the above list, the back-end and front-end developers needs to know a lot of things. A full-stack developer needs to know all things.
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
