<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Other | GeeKhmer]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/categories/other/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-06T14:29:32+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Bunlong Van]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[bunlong.van@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Freelancer]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2016/03/22/the-freelancer/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-22T16:45:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2016/03/22/the-freelancer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/the_freelancer.jpg" width="600" alt="The Freelancer" />
</p>




<p>
  Freelancer is a self-employed person who pursues a profession without a long-term commitment to any particular employer. Your curiosity in this opportunity was probably sparked by posts marked "Freelance" or "Work from anywhere" on the myriad of job boards around the Web. Freelancing is equal parts freedom and responsibility. While you have the freedom to choose when you work, where you work and what you work on, you are also responsible for everything: deadlines, finding work, the quality of your work, communication and so much more.
</p>




<p>
  So, your skill may be in Web development, Graphic design and your approach is to freelance, but it’s not that easy: freelancing is no walk in the park. It could become a living nightmare if you’re not able to use your time efficiently and remain focused and motivated until a project comes to a close. It could also become a nightmare if you market yourself poorly, are constantly desperate for work or surrender too much power to a client, putting you in the position of a monkey-worker responding to petty demands. The reasons I love being a freelancer:
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Be your own boss</strong><br/>
  Report to no one but yourself. You will work on boring tasks.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Enjoy your freedom</strong><br/>
  You have the freedom to work when and where you please, the freedom to structure your day as you please.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Choose what to work on</strong><br/>
  Want to spend 50% of your time on open-source projects? Interested in building your own Web app? You have the power to make that a reality. Want to work exclusively on projects in social media? Make it happen.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Set your rates</strong><br/>
  Value is both a reflection of how you perceive yourself and how others perceive you. Are you capable of meeting deadlines, communicating well and delivering quality code?
</p>




<p>
  If you are just starting out, charging $80 per hour will be hard; you have to earn that rate over time and with experience.
</p>




<p>
  So far so good, That's it!!! See ya!!! :)
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Continuous Learning]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2016/03/21/continuous-learning/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-21T14:15:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2016/03/21/continuous-learning</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/continuous_learning.jpg" width="600" alt="Continuous Learning" />
</p>




<p>
  <strong>WE LIVE IN INTERESTING TIMES.</strong> As development gets distributed across the globe, you learn there are lots of people capable of doing your job. <strong> You need to keep learning to stay marketable.</strong> Otherwise you'll become a dinosaur, stuck in the same job until, one day, you'll no longer be needed or your job get out-sourced to some cheaper resource.
</p>




<p>
  So what do you do about it? Here's a list of ways to keep you learning. Many of these can be found on the Internet for free:
</p>




<p>
  + Read books, magazines, blogs, Twitter feeds, and websites. If you want to go deeper into a subject, consider joining a mailing list or new group.
</p>




<p>
  + If you really want to get immersed in a technology, get hand on--write some code.
</p>




<p>
  + A good way to learn something is to teach or speak about it. When people are going to listen to you and ask you questions, you'll be highly motivated to learn. Try a lunch learn at work, a user group, or a local conference.
</p>




<p>
  + Join or start a study group or a local user group for a languages, technology, or discipline you are interested in.
</p>




<p>
  + Go to conferences. And if you can't go, many conferences put their talks on line for free.
</p>




<p>
  + Long commute? Listen to podcasts.
</p>




<p>
  + Follow the advice of the Pragmatic Programmers and learn a new language every year.
</p>




<p>
  + Not everything you learn has to be about technology. Learn the domain you're working in so you can better understand the requirements and help solve the business problem. Learning how to be more productive--how to work better--is another good option.
</p>




<p>
  + Go back to school.
</p>




<p>
  You don't have to spend every waking hour learning. A little time--say, each week--is better than nothing. There is (or should be) a life outside of work.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Technology changes fast. Don't get left behind.</strong>
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Learn To Code Movement]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2016/03/14/the-learn-to-code-movement/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-14T15:49:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2016/03/14/the-learn-to-code-movement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/the_learn_to_code_movement.jpg" width="600" alt="The Learn To Code Movement" />
</p>




<p>
  I’ve started to wonder if by focusing so much on learning code, we’re losing focus on how to support one of our most important assets in the technology industry.
</p>




<p>
  Technology and languages change constantly, so what was taught in a college coding class a few years ago is now outdated.
</p>




<p>
  This is a big problem, and one that will only become more severe over time. Just think about an iOS developer who in a few years might be coding entirely in Swift , Apple’s newly launched language. This type of rapid change is absent from almost all other industries, yet remains a serious concern for us.
</p>




<p>
  Here are just a few ideas that come to mind:
</p>




<p>
  <strong>1. Encourage pair programming</strong><br/>
  In case you’re not familiar, this is where two programmers work on the same computer at the same time so they can solve problems together. Every programmer has different strengths and weaknesses, so taking time to code together with different people in the company can be a great learning experience.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>2. Make learning free</strong><br/>
  A lot of technology companies offer some pretty awesome benefits, like catered lunches, healthy snacks and gym memberships. Education should be a part of that, too. Give employees budgets to buy educational books, or offer to pay for couple technical conferences a year that they may want to attend. The easier you make it for your team to continue learning, the more likely they are to take advantage of educational resources—and that ultimately helps both them and your company.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>3. Set learning time during work hours</strong><br/>
  Some companies set aside a few hours every week for everyone to stop working and spend time doing something that makes them better. This could be taking a typing class, playing an online programming course, refactoring some old code, or even coding a side project using a new language.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Not one way to learning but many.</strong>
</p>




<p>
  learning is a personal process and different things work for different people. Some people like books, others prefer online videos, and some just like to dig in and experiment. The best way to tackle different learning styles is by having a good mix of tools—and ways for developers to get access to them—so they continue to grow in the way that’s best for them.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Have you successfully implemented an education program for your development team?</strong>
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[3 Ways to Motivate People to Work Harder Faster and Smarter]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2016/03/09/3-ways-to-motivate-people-to-work-harder-faster-and-smarter/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-09T15:32:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2016/03/09/3-ways-to-motivate-people-to-work-harder-faster-and-smarter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/3_ways_to_motivate_people_to_work_harder_faster_and_smarter.png" width="600" alt="3 Ways to Motivate People to Work Harder Faster and Smarter" />
</p>




<p>
  <strong>1. Threaten them.</strong>
</p>




<p>
  <strong>2. Pay them lots of money.</strong>
</p>




<p>
  <strong>3. Make their work/work space fun.</strong>
</p>




<p>
  In today's workplace, threatening people has not been effective. Paying them lots of money (even if you can afford it) has only shown short-term success. Only number three, making their workplace enjoyable, has a track record of effecting real change. It is time managers learned how to create an atmosphere that is challenging, creative and fun for employees as well as for themselves.
</p>


<p>{% blockquote %}
FUN IS PRODUCTIVE
{% endblockquote %}</p>

<p>
  Imagine a work world where people love their work environment, and they are calm, stress-free and happy all day long. People who are in good spirits are more likely to be productive. Their mental attitude produces increased oxygen, endorphins, and blood flow to the brain, which enables them to think more clearly and creatively. They are more relaxed, more accepting of others, and more likely to share their sense of humor.
</p>




<p>
  Laughter creates a bond that brings others together; people like to be with employees who are having fun. Creativity, intuition and flexibility are key to successful operation of organizations today. In stimulating environments, employees enjoy their time at work and they will also excel at work. A fun workplace is not only more productive, but it attracts people and profits.
</p>




<p>
  So far so good take it easy... let create a Fun Workplace... :)
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[52 Simple Things to Be Your Best Every Day]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2016/02/25/52-simple-things-to-be-your-best-every-day/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-25T14:46:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2016/02/25/52-simple-things-to-be-your-best-every-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/52_simple _things.png" width="500" alt="52 Simple Things to Be Your Best Every Day" />
</p>




<p>
  Millions of people go to work every day, but they don't bring the best parts of themselves to the job--often because they don't know how. They may be stuck in a rut, never quite able to feel they're doing truly excellent work.
</p>




<p>
  If you like what you do and you want to take it to the next level, concentrate on these 52 simple things.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>1. Make people feel special:</strong> encourage and empower people at every chance.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>2. Find work you love and put your heart and soul into it:</strong> choose a job you love and you will never have to work another day in your life.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>3. Focus on the task at hand:</strong> do the best you can where you are with what you have.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>4. Treat every task as important:</strong> every job is a self-portrait of the person who does it.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>5. Always do the right thing, even when it's hard:</strong> don't let what you cannot do interfere with what you can.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>6. Delegate whenever you can:</strong> you get the best out of people when you believe in their talent.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>7. Take initiative:</strong> even if you're already very good at your job, do whatever you can to push your limits.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>8. Be part of the solution:</strong> don't be known as someone who is always complaining about something.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>9. Tell the truth:</strong> let people know they can count on you to be honest even when it creates difficulties.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>10. Help as many people as you can along the way:</strong> become someone people seek out for assistance.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>11. Avoid gossip always:</strong> it should go without saying, but turn a deaf ear to gossip and rumors.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>12. Maintain a positive attitude:</strong> a positive attitude is always contagious.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>13. Double your income by tripling your knowledge:</strong> don't let your knowledge and skills become outdated.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>14. Mind your emotions:</strong> when you're angry, count to 10; before you speak, count to 100.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>15. Make small daily improvements for stunning results:</strong> most of the time, success consists of a series of little daily efforts.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>16. Sharpen your skills and focus on mastering your talents:</strong> avoid boredom--and learn a new skill to keep you on top of your game.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>17. Be masterful at what you do despite the obstacles:</strong> no person fails who does their best.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>18. Don't feed your fears:</strong> have faith that you will make it through.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>19. Always be prepared:</strong> success occurs when opportunity meets preparation.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>20. Ask for help when you need it:</strong> there is no such thing as a self-made person; you will reach your goals only with the help of others.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>21. Set goals and get results:</strong> it's important to know where you are going, how you will get there, and what the outcome will be.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>22. Be all that you can be:</strong> don't settle for less than your highest potential.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>23. Don't worry about getting credit for getting things done:</strong> you can accomplish almost anything if you don't worry about who gets the credit.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>24. Preserve your integrity:</strong> make daily choices that are consistent with your values.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>25. Be a good role model:</strong> live by your values and walk your talk.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>26. Don't accept "good enough":</strong> do everything with excellence.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>27. Persevere with persistence:</strong> success is largely a matter of hanging on long after others have let go.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>28. Consider leadership something that exists wherever you are:</strong> make the most of yourself in every situation.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>29. Say please and thank you:</strong> it really does matter.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>30. Show respect:</strong> the more you give, the more you receive.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>31. Accept responsibility:</strong> take full responsibility with full confidence to get the job done well.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>32. Be determined to be your best:</strong> the difference between the impossible and the possible lies in your determination.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>33. Remember you are what you think:</strong> it is important to accentuate the positive and eliminate the negative.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>34. Erase your limitations:</strong> when you can conquer your fears, it's like lifting a hundred pounds of cement off your shoulders.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>35. Treat failure as a step toward success:</strong> failure is never fatal, but not trying is.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>36. Be trustworthy:</strong> make promises and keep your word.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>37. Become an expert:</strong> make the most of your knowledge.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>38. Respect people's time:</strong> everyone is busy. when you have someone's attention, be quick and succinct.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>39. Be an active listener:</strong> make sure you listen at least as much as you speak.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>40. Honor your commitments:</strong> when you make a promise, keep it.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>41. Be a great team player:</strong> maximize your contribution.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>42. Let go of restrictions:</strong> don't be limited by the scope of your thinking. Think big and succeed big.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>43. Deliver results:</strong> when you are given a directive, get it done well and on time.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>44. Be transparent:</strong> the more transparent you are with information, the more people will understand why you do what you do.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>45. Be kind:</strong> be unfailingly kind, polite, and gracious with everyone you meet--no matter what his or her role, and no matter how you're feeling.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>46. Manage your stress:</strong> take every action to minimize stress at work, because you don't want it to get the best of you.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>47. Be dependable:</strong> be consistent in yourself and reliable in your performance.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>48. Communicate with heart:</strong> sincerity helps you avoid many blunders and misunderstandings.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>49. Work with purpose:</strong> bring meaning to everything you do.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>50. Be true to yourself:</strong> everything you do should represent who you are.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>51. Make every moment count:</strong> we do not count years until there is nothing else to count.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>52. Lead from within:</strong> everything you need for a successful life is within you now.
</p>




<p>
  So far so good, That's it!!! See ya!!! :)
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
