<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Other | GeeKhmer]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/categories/other/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-03T23:50:35+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Bunlong Van]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[bunlong.van@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Development Stack]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2015/06/03/my-development-stack/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-03T23:27:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2015/06/03/my-development-stack</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  I always try to improve my development stack in order to gain productivity. And during the last few months, there has been a lot of change.
</p>




<p>
  Here is my current development stack that I use to create web apps:
</p>




<h3>
  Front-End
</h3>




<p>
  <strong>Bootstrap:</strong> A great HTML/CSS framework. It helps you build MVC very fast. Sass: A language compiled into CSS which adds many features such as variables, imports and functions.<br/>
  <strong>Sass:</strong> A language compiled into CSS which adds many features such as variables, imports and functions.<br/>
  <strong>Jquery:</strong> Good old Jquery, indeed. I may start to use angular in the next few weeks if I have enough time.
</p>




<h3>
  Back-End
</h3>




<p>
  <strong>Ruby on Rails:</strong> The most productive web framework I have ever worked with, much faster than any PHP framework, and enforcing many good software engineering practices.<br/>
  <strong>PostgreSQL:</strong> Faster and most powerful than most RDBMS (including MySQL), and free.
</p>




<h3>
  Hosting
</h3>




<p>
  <strong>Heroku:</strong> A great PaaS, and free for small apps. I also tried Google App Engine but its lack of flexibility was a problem for me.<br/>
  <strong>Cloudflare:</strong> It makes your app load faster and gives you a free SSL certificate.<br/>
  <strong>Mandrill:</strong> Very easy to use, yet powerful, EaaS (Email as a Service). I use it to send transactional emails like welcome messages and password resets.
</p>




<h3>
  Deployment
</h3>




<p>
  <strong>Git:</strong> I configured it with a pre-commit hook which automatically runs rails tests. And thanks to Heroku a simple push deploys my code. It’s very useful and now I just couldn’t go back.
</p>




<h3>
  Monitoring
</h3>




<p>
  <strong>Pingdom:</strong> A great tool to receive alerts if your app goes down (and if you add IFTTT you can receive them by SMS).
</p>




<p>
  Let’s see what it looks like (with the help of a great website I recently found):
</p>




<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/my_development_stack.png" alt="My Development Stack" />
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Top 8 Ruby on Rails Websites]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2015/05/21/top-8-ruby-on-rails-websites/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-21T14:44:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2015/05/21/top-8-ruby-on-rails-websites</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/happy_ruby_on_rails.jpg" width="400" alt="How Technology Company Make Money?" />
</p>




<p>
  If you are curious to know which sites are built with Ruby on Rails, then this article is for you. In a previous blog we have mentioned that startups tend to choose Ruby on Rails for a variety of reason. Same reasons reflect here. These 8 following sites use the framework or at least these were built with Ruby on Rails initially.
</p>




<p>
  <strong><a href="https://twitter.com/" target="_blank">TWITTER</a></strong><br/>
  Twitter is the most popular micro blogging platform in the world. It was envisioned by Dorsey as the sms of the internet. Twitter was first developed in 2006 with public release in 2007. It was developed in Ruby on Rails. Later it shifted its framework due to scalability. Like we said, startups have some special interest in Ruby on Rails.
</p>




<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/screen_twitter.png" width="500" alt="How Technology Company Make Money?" />
</p>




<p>
  <strong><a href="http://www.shopify.com/" target="_blank">SHOPIFY</a></strong><br/>
  Shopify is SaaS e-commerce platform. Basically, the merchants subscribes and uses Shopify for selling their product online or in store. Shopify was developed by Lütke in Ruby on Rails. He spent two months to develop the e-commerce platform for their snowboarding website. Interestingly, he did it because he was very dissatisfied with the existing platforms. In 2006, Shopify opened up to merchant and began enjoying significant growth.
</p>




<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/screen_shopify.png" width="500" alt="How Technology Company Make Money?" />
</p>




<p>
  <strong><a href="http://www.shopify.com/" target="_blank">GROUPON</a></strong><br/>
  Groupon is a deal of the day platform that issues discounted gift certificate a buy can use at variety of stores. Groupon was initially build with Ruby on Rails. It has enjoyed significant growth and now has 3 billion+ market capitalization. However, its business model has been heavily criticized since it inception. The criticism has been further bolstered by steady decline in sales and the ousting of the Founder-CEO Mr. Andrew D. Mason.
</p>




<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/screen_groupon.png" width="500" alt="How Technology Company Make Money?" />
</p>




<p>
  <strong><a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/" target="_blank">BLOOMBERG</a></strong><br/>
  Bloomberg is a private software, data and media company. It currently employs 15000 employees. Bloomberg provides analytical and stock trading platform, data and news services to companies through Bloomberg terminal.
</p>




<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/screen_bloomberg.png" width="500" alt="How Technology Company Make Money?" />
</p>




<p>
  <strong><a href="https://soundcloud.com/" target="_blank">SOUNDCLOUD</a></strong><br/>
  SoundCloud is a social platform for sound. It is like audio youtube where anybody can upload any sound or tunes and share them publicly or privately. Today, everyone is on multiple social platform. This has added a new dimension to SoundCloud. It is growing everyday and becoming a concern for other paid platform like iTunes and Google Play.
</p>




<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/screen_soundCloud.png" width="500" alt="How Technology Company Make Money?" />
</p>




<p>
  <strong><a href="https://squareup.com/global/en-gb/register" target="_blank">SQUARE</a></strong><br/>
  Square is making commerce easier for both enterprises and consumers. It was co-founded by twitter.com co-founder Dorsey. It makes credit card readers and stands that are attached with phones and tables. Users swap cards through these readers and make purchases.
</p>




<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/screen_square.png" width="500" alt="How Technology Company Make Money?" />
</p>




<p>
  <strong><a href="https://github.com/" target="_blank">GITHUB</a></strong><br/>
  The hub is the social platform for programmers. Git works a repository where coders push codes and conduct review. It is a leading website for code share. If you are a programmer/ developer applying for a job, many times perhaps you have noticed employers asking for your Github username to see your work. Github significantly facilitates the development of web application.
</p>




<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/screen_github.png" width="500" alt="How Technology Company Make Money?" />
</p>




<p>
  <strong><a href="http://www.slideshare.net/" target="_blank">SLIDESHARE</a></strong><br/>
  Another site built with Ruby on Rails is Slideshare. Slideshare is one of the most popular education and e-learning platform. It hosts different presentation slides and documents from users. Headed by CEO and Co-founder Ms. Rashmi Sinha, Slideshare is growing in popularity every day. It supports PowerPoint, PDF, Keynote and OpenDocument and also it hosts variety of documents from users.
</p>




<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/screen_slideshare.png" width="500" alt="How Technology Company Make Money?" />
</p>




<p>
  The article merely introduces the sites, does not go into technicalities. The purpose was to show you that there are many strong web platform that use the Ruby on Rails. If you are interested to use Ruby on Rails for your next project, you can choose Ruby on Rails and for that
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Technology Company Make Money?]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2015/05/20/how-technology-company-make-money/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-20T17:22:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2015/05/20/how-technology-company-make-money</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/how_tech_company_make_money.png" width="400" alt="How Technology Company Make Money?" />
</p>




<p>
  Have you ever wonder how the companies that offer free services make money? Such as Instagram, Evernote, Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, Google Maps, so on... or if it is even profitable to keep free users using their services. We would go through several revenue models and hopefully, it will throw you some light next time you decide to roll your own startup.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Revenues Models</strong><br/>
  Let’s start first giving some perspective what models are actually giving the most revenues. In 2013, App Store, reported that free apps brought the 71% of the revenue! Even more than paid apps... how’s that even possible?
</p>




<p>
  Ok, let’s discuss some revenue models to understand this. There are 8 main models.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Freemium:</strong> apps are free to download and use. However, quite often some different features are sold separately (e.g. new levels, specialized functions, remove ads, more capacity, and so on). E.g. Pandora, Hulu, Google Docs.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Premium:</strong> users paid upfront a fixed price for the application. After you pay for it, you are able to download it. Usually new software updates are free. E.g. MS Office 365.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Subscription:</strong> users paid a fixed price which is automatically charged every certain time. Magazines in the iOS Newsstand are a good example of this subscription based model. Subscriptions have generally lower prices than premium accounts. E.g. Netfix.
</p>




<p>
  Freemium is not as "free" as it might seem in the surface, there are indirect ways of getting revenues from it.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Advertising:</strong> the application/service is free to use, but it contains ads or interruption banners for an couple of minutes in order to raise revenue. This model is usually applied along with freemium apps and to remove the ads users have to pay a subscription. E.g. Spotify.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Selling data:</strong> user information and behavior inside the application is sell to interested 3rd-parties. Usually used with freemium apps and specified in the terms of used.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Transaction:</strong> the application is free to use generally and charges a percentage or fixed fee with every users’ transaction made. For example, it allows you to publish your item on their site for free but when you sell it, it charges you a fee. Or publish a project in a site and when it reaches certain goal a percentage fee is applied. E.g. eBay, Kickstarter.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Online lead generation:</strong> collects user’s information sometimes in an exchange of a product or service and then resell the information to companies interested indirectly. It’s different from the selling data model because the information is not sold to 3rd party directly, but indirectly. Influencing users desitions based on 3rd party companies affiliated and users’ interests, likes and behaviors. E.g. Mint, LinkedIn.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Donations:</strong> (it’s self-explanatory) Services/apps are free, but it encourages users to contribute throughout donations to support the development.
</p>




<p>
  After reading these, you might have more clues why free apps are so much win nowadays. They helped to create those million-dollar-per-day games! (remembered FlappyBird, Candycrush, Farmville…) In a market where there is enough competition, having a free option will take you to large numbers of users quicker and broader, because of the low barrier to entry. For instance, Whatsapp had at certain point 10k of daily downloads, after moving it to $1 it download rate drops 10 times, they finally opted for yearly subscriptions.
</p>




<p>
  Subscription-based revenue are also a model worth doing a special mention. It brings a steady flow of income to companies and usually comes in different tiers to fulfill users need. But, it has to be flexible enough, because it might limit hard core users which might be willing to pay more for taking the product to a new level.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>How does Instagram make money?</strong><br/>
  Freemium: Before selling to Facebook they were not making money. They are trying to incorporate Ads.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>How does Facebook make money?</strong><br/>
  Advertising & Freemium: Advertising is the main source of revenue but also some small percentage comes from payments, web apps and other sources.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>How does Whatsapp make money?</strong><br/>
  Freemium & Subscribers: The company is based on Freemium model for firt year. Later, it has a subscription of $1 per year.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>How does Twitter make money?</strong><br/>
  Advertising & Freemium: Mostly on corporate advertising and payments from 'promoted' tweets.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>How does Kickstarter make money?</strong><br/>
  Transactions/Royalties: Charges a 5% for successfully funded projects.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>How does Skype make money?</strong><br/>
  Freemium & Subscribers: Skype-to-skype calls are free, but users can buy additional features.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>How does Groupon make money?</strong><br/>
  Freemium & Transactions/Royalties: Groupon takes charges a fee to seller for every deal sold. It's one of the fastest growing company in the world. Going from $30.5 million in year one to $713.4 million in year two.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>How does Mint make money?</strong><br/>
  Lead Gen: Mint get paid a small fee when user switch to a new bank or company.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>How does Linkedin make money?</strong><br/>
  Advertising, Freemium, Subscribers & Selling Data: Sells user's data to companies and recruiters.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>How does Amazon Kindle make money?</strong><br/>
  Premium: Amazon loses money with Kindle but at the same time makes money selling digital content on it.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>How does Microsoft Xbox Kindle make money?</strong><br/>
  Advertising, Freemium, Subscribers, Premium & Transactions/Royalties: Xbox console and games cost money (premium), charges $50 annually (subscribers) in addition to ads.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>How does Stack Overflow make money?</strong><br/>
  Advertising: Ads, banners and sponsored results.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>How does Netflix make money?</strong><br/>
  Subscribers: Just subscribers.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>How does Pandora make money?</strong><br/>
  Advertising, Freemium & Subscribers: For free users presents adds, for subscribers does not.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>How does Pandora make money?</strong><br/>
  Advertising, Freemium & Subscribers: For free users presents adds, for subscribers does not.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>How does Spotify make money?</strong><br/>
  Advertising, Freemium & Subscribers: It has been reporting loses for a couple of years due to royalty payments.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>How does Firefox make money?</strong><br/>
  Transactions/Royalties: Most of the income comes from royalties from the Firefox search box. Their search partners includes Google, Bing, Yahoo, Yandex, Amazon, eBay and others. Also donations and grants.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>How does Craigslist make money?</strong><br/>
  Advertising, Freemium & Transactions/Royalties: Ads and charging users for posting in selected categories.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>How does Dropbox make money?</strong><br/>
  Freemium, Subscribers & Transactions/Royalties: A fixed capacity for free, to increase it users have to subscribe.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>How does Google make money?</strong><br/>
  Advertising: Ad products is their main source of revenue (AdSense and AdWords).
</p>




<p>
  <strong>How does Shopify make money?</strong><br/>
  Subscribers & Transactions/Royalties: Ad products is their main source of revenue (AdSense and AdWords).
</p>




<p>
  <strong>How does Airbnb make money?</strong><br/>
  Subscribers & Transactions/Royalties: Charge to travelers a fee of 6-12% and hosts pay a 3% for every booking on their site.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>How does Zynga make money?</strong><br/>
  Advertising & Freemium: Zynga makes money through people purchasing credits for games and also throught partnerships.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>How does World Of Warcraft make money?</strong><br/>
  Advertising & Subscribers: Charges $15 per month to users. They also sends expasions packs and discs.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>How does Hulu make money?</strong><br/>
  Advertising & Subscribers: Free service has Ads, limitations and restrictions, which are removed for subscribed users.
</p>




<p>
  So far so good, That it!!! See ya!!! :)
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enable Compression for Nginx]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2015/05/11/enable-compression-for-nginx/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-11T15:08:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2015/05/11/enable-compression-for-nginx</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/nginx-plus.png" width="500" alt="Enable Compression for Nginx" />
</p>




<p>
  Using Nginx for your Rails app? Use this trick to speed up your site. If you are using Nginx, you can quickly and easily speed up your site by enabling gzip compression for your application. Gzip compression compresses files and assets before they are sent to the client, resulting in a nice little speed boost. A sample of how to do this is listed below:
</p>


<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><figcaption><span>nginx.conf </span></figcaption>
 <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="n">server</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">listen</span> <span class="mi">80</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">server_name</span> <span class="n">mysite</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">com</span> <span class="n">www</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">mysite</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">com</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">root</span> <span class="sr">/opt/m</span><span class="n">ysite</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">com</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="n">current</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="kp">public</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">passenger_enabled</span> <span class="n">on</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">gzip</span> <span class="n">on</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">gzip_http_version</span> <span class="mi">1</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">gzip_vary</span> <span class="n">on</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">gzip_comp_level</span> <span class="mi">6</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">gzip_proxied</span> <span class="n">any</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">gzip_types</span> <span class="n">text</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="n">plain</span> <span class="n">text</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="n">html</span> <span class="n">text</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="n">css</span> <span class="n">application</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="n">json</span> <span class="n">application</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="n">javascript</span> <span class="n">application</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="n">x</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="n">javascript</span> <span class="n">text</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="n">javascript</span> <span class="n">text</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="n">xml</span> <span class="n">application</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="n">xml</span> <span class="n">application</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="n">rss</span><span class="o">+</span><span class="n">xml</span> <span class="n">application</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="n">atom</span><span class="o">+</span><span class="n">xml</span> <span class="n">application</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="n">rdf</span><span class="o">+</span><span class="n">xml</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>
  The gzip types specifies the mime types that will be compressed using the gzip protocol. You can exclude and include other mime types using this particular list. It's best not to include things such as images and/or media files.
</p>




<p>
  So far so good, That's it!!! See ya!!! :)
</p>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quickly Add Bootstrap to Your Project]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2015/04/16/quickly-add-bootstrap-to-your-project/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-16T08:52:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2015/04/16/quickly-add-bootstrap-to-your-project</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/bootstrap.png" alt="Quickly Add Bootstrap to Your Project" />
</p>




<p>
  Bootstrap is an amazing layout library that is awesome for building both prototypes as well as full blown websites. This very website makes extensive use of Bootstrap 3 to make things look awesome on both mobiles sites as well as the desktop.
</p>




<p>
  What if we want to quickly prototype out a site using bootstrap? Fortunately you can easily add bootstrap to your site without downloading anything, simply reference the associated files on the Yandex CDN. 
</p>




<p>
  Yandex is a worldwide search engine that is extremely popular in russia. Their CDN is extremely fast and has many different libraries available. To add bootstrap via yandex, simply include them like so (this also include jQuery, since Bootstrap JS requires it).
</p>


<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='javascript'><span class='line'><span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="err">/p&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="nx">script</span> <span class="nx">src</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">&quot;http://yandex.st/jquery/1.11.1/jquery.min.js&quot;</span><span class="o">&gt;&lt;</span><span class="err">/script&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="nx">p</span><span class="o">&gt;&lt;</span><span class="nx">link</span> <span class="nx">href</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">&quot;http://yandex.st/bootstrap/3.1.1/css/bootstrap.min.css&quot;</span> <span class="nx">media</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">&quot;screen&quot;</span> <span class="nx">rel</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">&quot;stylesheet&quot;</span> <span class="o">/&gt;&lt;</span><span class="err">/p&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="nx">script</span> <span class="nx">src</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">&quot;http://yandex.st/bootstrap/3.1.1/js/bootstrap.min.js&quot;</span><span class="o">&gt;&lt;</span><span class="err">/script&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="nx">p</span><span class="o">&gt;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>
  A full list of the libraries available can be found on the <a href="https://tech.yandex.ru/jslibs/" target="_blank">yandex</a> website. Note that it's in russian, so you might need to translate it.
</p>




<p>
  So far so good, That's it!!! See ya!!! :)
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
