<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Other | GeeKhmer]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/categories/other/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-30T10:23:46+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Bunlong Van]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[bunlong.van@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Workshop - Learn Ruby On Rails in a Weekend]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2014/08/29/workshop-learn-ruby-on-rails-in-a-weekend/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-29T14:56:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2014/08/29/workshop-learn-ruby-on-rails-in-a-weekend</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/ruby_on_rails.png" width="400" />
</p>




<h3>Let's Start</h3>




<p>
  Have you always wanted to learn Ruby on Rails but never found the time to do so?<br/>
  Have you been reading articles and watching videos on Ruby on Rails but wish that someone could be by your side to answer your burning questions?
</p>




<p>
  This weekend workshop is designed to make you feel confident about what Ruby on Rails can do for you, and you'll graduate from the class with knowledge on building web applications for fun or profit.
</p>




<p>
  In the 2 days, you'll be doing lots of coding, In the process, you'll learn about web design, application design process, database usage, and most importantly, the web application framework that Groupon, and many others were built with - Ruby on Rails.
</p>




<h3>You Will Learn</h3>




<p>
  <strong>1. Development Environment Setup</strong><br/>
  Learn to set up a 'development environment' on your machine, and be introduced to the various open source tools and online services.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>2. Application and Database Design</strong><br/>
  Learn to decompose everyday problems into conceptual models that can be coded into a web application.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>3. Web Design</strong><br/>
  Learn basic HTML, CSS using the Bootstrap library to create beautiful and functional web applications.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>4. Ruby on Rails</strong><br/>
  Learn fundamentals of Ruby on Rails and be wowed by its magic and simplicity.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>5. Your Own App</strong><br/>
  Learn to build your own social networking app using Ruby on Rails.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>6. Cloud Deployment</strong><br/>
  Learn to deploy your web application to the cloud so that your friends can use it too.
</p>




<h3>Who can join?</h3>




<p>
  - Beginners, with great attitude and a strong will for learning Ruby on Rails.<br/>
  - Experienced programmers, who are new to web development or Ruby on Rails.
</p>




<h3>What to prepare?</h3>




<p>
  - Completed exercises on tryruby.org.<br/>
  - Your laptop to be installed with Ruby 2.1 and Rails 4 (we'll get this done on Saturday).
</p>




<h3>Schedule</h3>




<p>
  <strong>First day</strong><br/>
  We'll get you setup with Ruby on Rails on your laptop in the first hour, and then we'll go through open source tools and online services like Git, Bundler, GitHub, Heroku... etc.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Second day</strong><br/>
  We'll start the day with creating a brand new Ruby on Rails app and setting it up with a home page. Unlike most courses, we'll not be using Rails scaffold, and you'll learn how to build an app from scratch, with your bare hands.<br/>
  We'll learn:<br/>
  - Simple Web Design with Bootstrap.<br/>
  - Application Design Process.<br/>
  - Setting up of Databases.<br/>
  - User Authentication.<br/>
  - Rails Models and Forms.<br/>
  - Model Validations.<br/>
  - Ajax Updates.<br/>
  - Deploy to Cloud.
</p>




<h3>What to bring?</h3>




<p>
  - Your laptop (and charger).<br/>
  - Your 'never say die' spirit.
</p>




<h3>Terms and Conditions</h3>




<p>
  Please bring your own laptop and charger. Internet is provided.<br/>
  The instructor reserves the rights to cancel the workshop if it does not have a minimum of 6 participants. 
</p>




<p>
  Place and Date will inform later. Note: <strong>Completed exercises on tryruby.org</strong>... Thank!!!
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guide to Become An Expert Ruby/Rails Developer]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2014/08/26/guide-to-become-an-expert-ruby-slash-rails-developer/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-26T09:35:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2014/08/26/guide-to-become-an-expert-ruby-slash-rails-developer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/guide_ruby_rails_developer.png" width="170" />
</p>




<p>
  This guide is meant to help you acquire the fundamental skills you need to become a Ruby Developer. Using books, video courses, and projects, you’ll learn how to develop web applications using Ruby, HTML & CSS, jQuery, and Rails. Additionally, you will learn about best practices, design patterns and principles, and the fundamentals of visual design. The goal is to build a solid foundation that you can expand on to become an expert Ruby Developer.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Required Reading and Courses</strong><br/>
  1. The Passionate Programmer by Chad Fowler.<br/>
  2. Online Ruby Course by Pragmatic Studios.<br/>
  3. HTML & CSS by Jon Duckett.<br/>
  4. Smashing CoffeeScript by Alex Hudson.<br/>
  5. Don’t Make Me Think by Steve Krug.<br/>
  6. Everyday Rails Testing with RSpec by Aaron Sumner.<br/>
  7. Online Ruby on Rails Course by Pragmatic Studios.<br/>
  8. Bootstrapping Design by Jarrod Drysdale.<br/>
  9. Practical Object-Oriented Design in Ruby by Sandi Metz.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>How To Use This Guide</strong><br/>
  The best way to use this guide is to start from the Ruby section and proceed towards the CoffeeScript and jQuery section. Each section has a Core Activity and an Assessment. The core activities are meant to teach you and the assessments are meant for you to practice solving problems on your own. There are additional readings for each section for the purposes of professional development. These readings can be done in-between study sessions or during your commute to work, but don’t skip them.  I encourage you to read the entire guide before you start doing anything. It’s a good idea to know where you will end up before you invest any time.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Setup Development Environment</strong><br/>
  Follow these <a href="https://github.com/thoughtbot/laptop" target="_blank">instructions</a> to setup your development environment for either Mac OS X or Linux. Download & install <a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/3" target="_blank">Sublime Text 3</a>
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Create a GitHub Account</strong><br/>
  Make sure you create a <a href="https://github.com/" target="_blank">GitHub account</a> if you don’t have one already. You’ll need a GitHub account in order to store and share your code with the world.
</p>




<p>
  So far so good, Continuous Learning to stay marketable.<br/>
  Take your time, see you in next article. :)
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RailsPanel]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2014/07/30/railspanel/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-30T08:30:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2014/07/30/railspanel</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  RailsPanel is a Chrome extension for Rails development that will end your tailing of development.log. Have all information about your Rails app requests in the browser - in the Developer Tools panel. Provides insight to db/rendering/total times, parameter list, rendered views and more.
</p>




<p>
  <a class="fancybox" href="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/rails_panel.png"><img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/rails_panel.png" width="680" /></a>
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Installation</strong><br/>
  To use this extension you need to add meta_request gem to your app's Gemfile:
</p>


<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><figcaption><span>Gemfile </span></figcaption>
 <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="n">group</span> <span class="ss">:development</span> <span class="k">do</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">gem</span> <span class="o">&amp;</span><span class="n">lsquo</span><span class="p">;</span><span class="n">meta_request</span><span class="o">&amp;</span><span class="n">rsquo</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">end</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>
  Install <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/railspanel/gjpfobpafnhjhbajcjgccbbdofdckggg" target="_blank">RailsPanel extension</a> from the Chrome WebStore. This is recommended way of installing extension, since it will auto-update on every new version. Note that you still need to update meta_request gem yourself.
</p>




<p>
  So far so good, Let play around with RailsPanel and enjoy your productivity. :)
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vim - The Best Programming Editor for UNIX]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2014/07/24/vim-the-best-programming-editor-for-unix/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-24T12:20:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2014/07/24/vim-the-best-programming-editor-for-unix</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  <a class="fancybox" href="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/vim.png"><img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/vim.png" width="680" /></a>
</p>




<p>
  Vim is an advanced text editor that provide the power of Unix editor 'Vi', with a more complete feature set.
</p>




<p>
  Vim is a highly configurable text editor built to enable efficient text editing. It is an improved version of the vi editor distributed with most UNIX systems.
</p>




<p>
  Vim is often called a "programmer's editor," and so useful for programming that many consider it an entire IDE. It's not just for programmers, Vim is perfect for all kinds of text editing, from composing email to editing configuration files.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Features</strong><br/>
  - highly configurable.<br/>
  - syntax highlightning.<br/>
  - windows split (both vertically as well as horrizontally).<br/>
  - tabbing.<br/>
  - folding.<br/>
  - unicode support.<br/>
  - flexible indenting.<br/>
  - ...
</p>




<p>
  <strong>The Good</strong><br/>
  Vim is a professional text editor targeting mainly programmers, but it can be also used by any other type of user.<br/>
  It received the best text editor award from readers of the Linux Journal magazine in 2001, 2002, 2003 , 2004 and 2005, which I think tells a lot about its efficiency.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>The Bad</strong><br/>
  The bad and ugly part about Vim would be for most users the fact that they must do the learning first in order to be able to use it.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>The Truth</strong><br/>
  Vim is a multi-platform text editor, Vim provides all the functionality of a regular text editor, such as spell checking, Unicode support, possibility of undo/redo the most recent actions, integrated help but it has also some features of its own which make it a powerful and reliable tool.
</p>




<p>
  So far so good, To get a better idea on what Vim is, you can also check <a href="http://www.vim.org/" target="_blank">www.vim.org</a> :)
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
