<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: other | GeeKhmer]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/categories/other/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-12-24T23:28:22+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Bunlong Van]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[bunlong.van@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jack Ma - The Economic Club of New York]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2016/12/24/jack-ma-the-economic-club-of-new-york/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-24T23:13:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekhmer.github.io/blog/2016/12/24/jack-ma-the-economic-club-of-new-york</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/jack_1.jpg" width="600" alt="Jack Ma - The Economic Club of New York" />
</p>




<p>
  I am so honored. I never expected so many people to come to listen to my talk. I felt so important sitting thereg thereg. How many of you have used ALIBABA's services? How many of you have never been to China? Never been to China. Thank you very much.
</p>




<p>
  Well, 20 years ago, I came to America. My first trip was to seattle. I learned so much about America. America is not what I learned from the books. In seattle, I found the internet. I came back and told my friends that I am going to open a company called INTERNET. I invited 24 of my friends and headed to our discussion, and finnally we had a vote. 23 of them against me. Forget about it, there is no such network called the internet. Don't do it. Only one person said, I trust you. I don't know what it is, but if you want to try, try it. I was 30 years old. with not knowing anything about computers, without knowing anything about business, I started my first company with my wife and a schoolmate. We brought $1000 to start the business. It was so difficult. I was a blind man writing on the back of blind tigers. riding on the back of blind tigers. For the first three years, life was really bad. I tried to bother borrow $3000 from a bank, it took me three years. Everyone said that Jack is telling a lie because there is no such network called the internet in 1996.
</p>




<p>
  One day, China was connected to the internet from Shanghai. I invited 10 friends to my apartment. I wanted to show them that I was not telling a lie. There is a network call the internet. We waited three and a half hours to download the first picture. I told him that in 10 years it would work. AT least it was true that I was not telling a lie.
</p>




<p>
  We tried to help our small business to sell online. Nobody wanted to sell because nobody wanted to buy. The first week, we had seven employees and we bought and sold ourselves. The second week, somebody started to buy on our website. We had two rooms full of things that we bought. Since 1995-1999, We go nowhere our business. Nothing was ready.
</p>




<p>
  In 1999, I invited 18 friends of mine to my apartment. We decided to do it again. We called it ELLIE BALA.com, and people said why ALLIE BOB ALLIE BOB. We used it because it's easy to spell and easy to remember. We have so many small business and small business it is so difficult for them to survive if we can use internet technology to help small business, it will be fantatic. We should help the small guys to save costs, because small business know how to save costs. Our business is helping small business to make money online. We want to make the company last for 100 years. 102 years. Why 102 years? because we were born in 1999. 102 will cross three centuries. Dont say were successful no matter how much money we make. No matter how much we achieve. We want to live 102 years. We have another 86 years to go. When I heard this club is 100 eight years old, I was surprised and shocked. Today, nobody believe that ALIBABA could survive. When we IPO, they said you are e-commerce, ALIBABA. 
</p>




<p>
  We are different. The difference between us and AMAZON is we do not buy and sell, but we help small business to buy and sell. We have 10 million small business on our site buying and selling every day. We have 10 million small businesses on our site buying and selling every day.We do not deliver our packages ourselves. We have more than 2 million people to help us deliver 13 million packages a day. We do not have warehouses, but we manage warehouses for other small and medium-size companies. We don't have our own inventories. But we do have more than 350 million buyers to shop every day on our site. Our revenue last year was 390 billion U.S. Dollars. This year, we will be bigger than WALMART globally. As WALMART managed, that size business has $2.3 million 2.3 million people. AMAZON people. AMAZON is a shopping center. You go there and buy things. In ALIBABA, it ther future picture you see like this, it's different. People are surprised. Here, e-commerce becomes a lifestyle. Young people use it to exchange I guess, communicate to exchange ideas, communicate. It's a lifestlye. This is how ther internet e-commerce is changing China. What we are proud of is not how much we sell. Yes, we are proud. We will sell one trillion U.S. dollars in five years. This is my goal. We think we will possibly make it. We are proud of that, but we are more proud because we provide 14 million jobs for China. We created the jobs in the countryside. We created jobs for women, over 51% of the power sellers on the internet are women. We can feel proud of that.
</p>




<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/jack_2.jpg" width="600" alt="Jack Ma - The Economic Club of New York" />
</p>




<p>
  People say, what next? what is the future? you are everywhere. 80% of the buying and selling online is created by our company. Our future is that we have to future to globalize our business. We want to globalize the infrastructure of e-commerce. Why internet e-commerce? why it grows faster in China than the USA? The infrastructure of commerce in China was not like here. You have all the shops offline, WALMART, KMART, but in China nothing so e-commerce in the U.S. is a desert. It is a comment to the main business. In China, it is the main course.
</p>




<p>
  We create the infrastructure. If we globalize our infrastructure, the payment, all over the world to sell everywhere, help glover global consumers to buy everwhere. In 10 years, we will help to billion consumers in the world to shop online. Anywhere in the world, you are shopping online and within 72 hours you will receive the product. Anywhere in the world, you are shopping online and within 72 hours you will receive the product. Anywhere in China, a shop online and you will receive the product within 24 hours. We think our globalization is focused on helping small business. Helping them to do is this in the most efficient way, and we think that we will help another 10 million businesses on our e-commerce platform. We will empower them, give them traffic, give them a payment system so they can do business anywhere easily and quickly. We will have 40 prisons 40% of business outside of China. Today we have only 2%. 
</p>




<p>
  What is your play in America? Are you going to come win and invade America? When are you going to compete with AMAZON or EBAY? I would say that we shall great respect for EBAY and AMAZON, but the opportunity and the strategy for us is helping small business in America to sell their products to China. Today, the middle class for China is almost the same as the American population. In 10 years, it will be more than 500 million Chinese people will be middle class. The demand for middle-class, good products, good service, so powerful, so strong, and I think China today cannot afford the good products, good service with the terrible air we have. I don't think China will be able to do that. China has been focused on exporting for the last 20 years. I think the next 20 years that China should be focused on importing, learn to buy, spent the money, by a lot of things globally. Buy a lot of things globally. You should use the internet, go to China. past 20 years, they companies all over China, but it is the greate opportunity for the use of e-commerce for small business to go to America. We have helped a lot of American farmers sell things to China. They the American ambassador to China asked us to sell the cherries in seattle. 80,000 farmers took the order, pickup up the cherries, ship them to China. 80,000 farmers, 160,000 tons of cherries, and last year 300 tons of cherries. I don't know what the year is about. We also had ALASKA seafood to help sell lobsters. 10 years they cannot sell it. We have a lot of American branded companies using site to sell. And cosco, they saved sold 600 tons of nuts on our site, 6.5 million dollars. If we can help sell lobsters and cherries, why we cannot have these small and media sized companies to China using our system. So this is what I want.</p>




<p>
  November 11, the singles they, we make that a shopping day. Last year for that day, we sold 9.7 billion U.S. dollars. For the first 10 minutes, we had 24 million people. This year, the number was scary. We need more American products to China. We have hungry 100 million people coming to buy every day. We do not come here to compete. We come here to bring the small business. In 10-20 years, buy anywhere, sell anywhere. This is how the internet is going to change. The power of changes so powerful. We have a factory and the first world war because of the strength of the arms to the second revolution is the energy, comapnies, and second world war. This time, internet, the data, and I think we have a new business called platform. And the third world work is going to happen, and this war is not between nations. This war will work together against disease, poverty, climate change, and I believe this is our future, the human being, the nation together. 
</p>




<p>
  <img src="http://geekhmer.github.io/images/jack_3.jpg" width="600" alt="Jack Ma - The Economic Club of New York" />
</p>




<p>
  Rely on the young people using computers, data to solve the problems, society problems, and this is what I am passionate about. It is not about the money. It is about dreams. It is the dreams that you believe that change the world. Today is difficult, and tomorrow is much more difficult, but the day after tomorrow is beautiful. Most people do lie most people die tomorrow evening. Thank you very much.
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
